<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beach Babies Nursery</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Beach Babies Nursery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning First Aid</title>
      <link>/news/2025/04/learning-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2025/04/learning-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>My reason for writing this deeply personal blog is in the hope that you will do some first aid training. I’d highly recommend doing a first aid course, but if you need a quick refresher, these videos are a great place to start: How to do CPR on an Adult - First Aid Training - St John Ambulance How to do Child CPR - First Aid Training - St John Ambulance You don’t need to be a teacher, nursery worker, or emergency services professional to do first aid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/nurseries/careers/nursery-practitioner-level-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nurseries/careers/nursery-practitioner-level-3/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for full-time Early Years Educators / Nursery Practitioners to join our friendly, enthusiastic and hard-working family at the Landbeach Nursery, just outside Cambridge.
What you’ll do:  Greet children each day with a warm, kind smile that makes them feel loved and welcomed. Be always ready to build a fully functional space rocket from a kitchen roll tube, 2 elastic bands, and a handful of pipe cleaners. Share songs, stories, and creative activities that everyone will enjoy (being in tune is optional, but knowing Frozen lyrics is a plus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nursery Availability</title>
      <link>/news/2024/09/nursery-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/09/nursery-availability/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge is booming. Many people move here for jobs, they set up home and start families. This is great for the area but despite what Cambridgeshire County Council may say there is a dire shortage of nursery provision in these growth areas.
I know that the government plans to reuse redundant classrooms in schools as nurseries. Setting aside the suitability of these for babies and toddlers, there aren’t redundant classrooms in the areas that need more nursery spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up naturally</title>
      <link>/news/2024/08/growing-up-naturally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/08/growing-up-naturally/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent decades thinking about how children can be best guided on their journey to be capable and resilient adults. I hasten to add that I didn’t do this with my own children, they can cite many examples of what I did differently, they were just the start of my reflection on childhood.
Here are a few of my guiding principles, they aren’t set in stone, they in turn will evolve as I learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy for Children</title>
      <link>/news/2024/07/philosophy-for-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/07/philosophy-for-children/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes at nursery we have discussions with the children that fall into the realms of philosophy. These are some of the most valuable, thought provoking talks that you can have with a child, they are when we talk about things that don’t have a right or a wrong answer.
When? This is a skills that can only really start from when you are aged 3 and works well from then on, in fact we all know adults who could benefit from something similar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We don’t all see the world in the same way - Recognising the value of creativity at every stage of a child’s development</title>
      <link>/news/2024/06/we-dont-all-see-the-world-in-the-same-way-recognising-the-value-of-creativity-at-every-stage-of-a-childs-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/06/we-dont-all-see-the-world-in-the-same-way-recognising-the-value-of-creativity-at-every-stage-of-a-childs-development/</guid>
      <description>We don’t all see the world in the same way Recognising the value of creativity at every stage of a child’s development Why imagination and creativity are important: From birth, children have unique responses to all that they see, hear, feel and experience in their daily lives. These responses can be physical, emotional, social or cultural. Babies in utero can respond to music and after they are born - as they grow, their responses will develop into movements to music, and potentially the ability to follow rhythm and create dance routines to represent their own emotional response to different genres of music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a schema?</title>
      <link>/news/2024/06/what-is-a-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/06/what-is-a-schema/</guid>
      <description>From birth, children repeat their actions and behaviours (schema) i.e. grasping, lifting, sucking, waving, banging, rolling, posting, connecting.
Children have a natural urge to do the same thing again and again. Just like you when you are learning a new skill such as knitting, riding a bike, gardening.
This repetitive behaviour helps children and adults to develop and deepen their understanding of concepts and helps them perfect the skills they are learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loose Parts</title>
      <link>/news/2024/05/loose-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/05/loose-parts/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever bought your child a toy and they have spent more time playing with the box than what was inside it? Have you ever collected stones and used them as jewels, coins or treasure? If you have, then you’ve already experienced loose parts.
Loose parts play is essentially using open ended objects to enhance natural curiosity and imagination in play.
The theorist and the theory The term ‘loose parts’ first came into use after the publication of an article entitled ‘The Theory of Loose Parts: How NOT to Cheat Children’ written in 1971 by an architect named Simon Nicholson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heuristic Play</title>
      <link>/news/2024/05/heuristic-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/05/heuristic-play/</guid>
      <description>Heuristic play Suitable for children aged from when they are capable crawlers up to 2 or 2 and a half years old
The theory: It is a child-led play where one or more children play with different objects and move around, often moving the objects with them. That sounds vague but it’s what toddlers do naturally, they move/fill/empty boxes and bags and carry them to other places. The key component is movement, for example a child may roll a cardboard tube across the floor before posting stones down it and watching them come out before moving on to stuffing fabric pieces down it and noticing a difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasure Baskets for Infant Development</title>
      <link>/news/2024/04/treasure-baskets-for-infant-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/04/treasure-baskets-for-infant-development/</guid>
      <description>Treasure baskets Suitable for children aged from about 6 months until they are capable crawlers
The theory These childrens brains are growing and forming neural pathways at an enormous rate. Every child has five senses; sight, hearing, touch, taste and smell, objects that they play with should appeal to these different senses. The more all the senses are engaged and stimulated the greater the neural development.
Babies learn from the treasure basket by looking, sucking, touching, licking, banging, picking up and dropping, shaking, by moving things from hand to mouth and looking carefully at objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Play</title>
      <link>/news/2024/04/understanding-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/04/understanding-play/</guid>
      <description>Before childhood existed Centuries ago there was no idea of childhood as a separate notion. Children were born and seen as younger people, they were dressed as adults and treated as such. They contributed to family life as they could, gathering food or water, caring for livestock or younger or sick relatives. Then in Victorian times they became a resource that could work outside the home which in turn led to the view of this as exploitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Years funding – What you should know</title>
      <link>/news/2024/03/early-years-funding-what-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/03/early-years-funding-what-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>The government is introducing more help for eligible working parents in a few stages over this year and next.
How Does It Work? The current funding for 3 &amp;amp; 4 year olds refers to 15 and 30 hours per week. These hours are across 38 weeks a year, a more accurate title would be either 570 or 1140 hours per year, so at Beach Babies which opens for 51 weeks a year this is a bit over 11 or 22 hours per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your work improve your life?</title>
      <link>/news/2024/01/does-your-work-improve-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/01/does-your-work-improve-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Discover the keys to achieving a fulfilling work-life balance in our latest blog article, where we explore practical strategies for enhancing well-being in the post-COVID world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beach Babies Approach to Undesired Behaviours</title>
      <link>/news/2023/10/beach-babies-approach-to-undesired-behaviours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/10/beach-babies-approach-to-undesired-behaviours/</guid>
      <description>As a setting we are often asked how we support children with undesired or tricky behaviours. Today, we share some of our strategies that are open ended and are embedded in our practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making The Most of The Long Summer Break</title>
      <link>/news/2023/07/making-the-most-of-the-long-summer-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/07/making-the-most-of-the-long-summer-break/</guid>
      <description>Explore a blend of imaginative, educational, and entertaining activities to keep your children engaged during the lengthy summer holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Super Nanny to Nursery Founder</title>
      <link>/news/2023/06/from-super-nanny-to-nursery-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/06/from-super-nanny-to-nursery-founder/</guid>
      <description>Beach Babies: Nurturing Children, Empowering Communities, and Ensuring a Sustainable Future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cost of childcare</title>
      <link>/news/2023/04/the-cost-of-childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/04/the-cost-of-childcare/</guid>
      <description>Childcare has made it to the top of the agenda. It was the headline in March’s budget, and even has articles in the Economist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to children about death</title>
      <link>/news/2023/04/talking-to-children-about-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/04/talking-to-children-about-death/</guid>
      <description>We discuss the importance of talking to children about death and provide tips on how to do so, such as using clear language and encouraging questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of tooth brushing</title>
      <link>/news/2023/01/the-importance-of-tooth-brushing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/01/the-importance-of-tooth-brushing/</guid>
      <description>We take a closer look at tooth brushing and explore why it&amp;rsquo;s something to be passionate about from an early age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it take to be Outstanding?</title>
      <link>/news/2022/11/what-does-it-take-to-be-outstanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/11/what-does-it-take-to-be-outstanding/</guid>
      <description>Beach Babies in Wilburton has recently been awarded Outstanding by Ofsted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deferring school entry</title>
      <link>/news/2022/10/deferring-school-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/10/deferring-school-entry/</guid>
      <description>This week, we dive into the hot topic of preparing your children for starting school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Beach Babies pays the Real Living Wage</title>
      <link>/news/2022/09/why-beach-babies-pays-the-real-living-wage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/09/why-beach-babies-pays-the-real-living-wage/</guid>
      <description>We take a good, long look at what we can do to make life better for our team and our business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EYFS is changing. Part 4: I know how to stay healthy and well</title>
      <link>/news/2022/05/the-eyfs-is-changing.-part-4-i-know-how-to-stay-healthy-and-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/05/the-eyfs-is-changing.-part-4-i-know-how-to-stay-healthy-and-well/</guid>
      <description>We explore one of our four major curriculum themes, &amp;lsquo;Learning how to take care of yourself&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Years funding – what you should know</title>
      <link>/news/2022/04/early-years-funding-what-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/04/early-years-funding-what-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>The government is introducing more help for eligible working parents in a few stages over this year and next.
How does it work? The current funding for 3 &amp;amp; 4 year olds refers to 15 and 30 hours per week. These hours are across 38 weeks a year, a more accurate title would be either 570 or 1140 hours per year, so at Beach Babies which opens for 51 weeks a year this is a bit over 11 or 22 hours per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EYFS is changing Part 3: Valuing Self and Others</title>
      <link>/news/2022/01/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-3-valuing-self-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/01/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-3-valuing-self-and-others/</guid>
      <description>We reflect on the values and ethos at the heart of our Beach Babies family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EYFS is changing  Part 2: Community Engagement at Beach Babies</title>
      <link>/news/2021/12/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-2-community-engagement-at-beach-babies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/12/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-2-community-engagement-at-beach-babies/</guid>
      <description>When the word ‘community’ is used in early years settings, often the first thing to come to mind is going on outings. Be it to the local park, postbox or even for a walk in the village. For us at Beach Babies, community means so much more than just going out of the setting.
 I want to take you back to the definition of the word community “a group of people living in the same place or having a particular characteristic in common”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EYFS is changing Part 1: I know how to care for the world I live in.</title>
      <link>/news/2021/11/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-1-i-know-how-to-care-for-the-world-i-live-in./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/11/the-eyfs-is-changing-part-1-i-know-how-to-care-for-the-world-i-live-in./</guid>
      <description>We at Beach Babies have always believed that children in our care are supported by us, allowing them to ‘grow up naturally’. We believe that a child who is enabled to grow up in a natural environment, who are themselves nurtured, and who experience the natural world every day, in every season know it and will care for it more.
  
  As a part of our renewed curriculum, one of the four areas we have identified as a foundation to all that we do is Caring for Our World; for children to know how to look after the world around them and all that is in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EYFS is changing Introduction: What will this look like at Beach Babies?</title>
      <link>/news/2021/10/the-eyfs-is-changing-introduction-what-will-this-look-like-at-beach-babies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/10/the-eyfs-is-changing-introduction-what-will-this-look-like-at-beach-babies/</guid>
      <description>In 2008 The Early Years Foundation Stage (EYFS) was made statutory for settings to follow. Its purpose was to provide children with consistent high-quality care within an inviting environment whilst keeping them safe and healthy. It gave settings clear information on how children learn and develop with a path of how they should reach the learning goals within the EYFS. Over the years it has been changed and adapted with the newest update being rolled out as of September 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have a new website but why?</title>
      <link>/news/2021/10/we-have-a-new-website-but-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/10/we-have-a-new-website-but-why/</guid>
      <description>The old one gave the basic information new families wanted, such as what age children we care for, when we are open and a feel for what we offer through the photos.
The previous one had been around for a decade, the children pictured on it have grown into secondary school-aged young people and Beach Babies has grown and developed as much as they have.
The new website shows how the nurseries and their grounds have matured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When taking small opportunities leads to the discovery of a passion</title>
      <link>/news/2021/02/when-taking-small-opportunities-leads-to-the-discovery-of-a-passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/02/when-taking-small-opportunities-leads-to-the-discovery-of-a-passion/</guid>
      <description>At Beach Babies we know that without our wonderful staff, we wouldn’t be where we are today. They are bright, passionate and full of the wonderful energy that brings smiles to the children’s faces each and every day.
Not all of our Nursery Practitioners realised this passion straight away, however.
You’ve probably met Chloe over at Wilburton. Did you know that she has just been accepted to The University of Cambridge to study for her PGCE?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things to do before you start school</title>
      <link>/news/2020/09/things-to-do-before-you-start-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/09/things-to-do-before-you-start-school/</guid>
      <description>The years before formal school are the time in your children’s lives when you can have the most influence. Set them free and encourage some healthy habits by focusing on doing these simple things. Full credit for the idea goes to the National Trust and their 50 things to do before you’re 11 &amp;amp; 3/4s.
 Learn to hop Build a den in a local park Climb a tree    Play conkers Play Pooh sticks Squelch your bare feet in soft mud Eat a meal in a den in your garden Do a treasure hunt Dance in summer rain, without a coat Make mud pieces Make your own perfume/potion Take a neighbour something you’re baked, like a biscuit Knead bread dough Balanced along a low wall on a walk Help start and put out a camp fire Peeled a stick using a potato peeler Post letter or card you’ve made yourself Run a stick along railings on a walk Made a sandcastle with a moat Played boo with a baby Painted your own face or body Washed up cooking things Learned to chop and prepare some fruit and vegetables Toasted food over a fire, marshmallows, smores etc When it’s sunny lie under a tree and look at the different greens of the leaves Lift a log or a rock and hold the insects, worms, woodlice etc Empty the dishwasher Jump out after hiding in a pick of autumn leaves Roll and run down hills, preferably whilst shouting ‘Weeeeeee’ Paint with your hands and feet Regularly go for a walk of at least a mile Eat and apple and blackberries straight from the tree or bush Spend a whole day in fancy dress, you can be a superstar Thank you for reading my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to nursery</title>
      <link>/news/2020/06/returning-to-nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/06/returning-to-nursery/</guid>
      <description>I have seen many scary reports from primary schools who reopened on 1st June. Each school has to apply the government’s guidance in a way that suits them and their setting. However, some news reports seem to feature schools that have implemented measures in excess of the government guidelines and that’s not what I see in our area.
 Things are different but not by as much as the reports would imply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home-schooling or not?</title>
      <link>/news/2020/04/home-schooling-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/04/home-schooling-or-not/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays my social media feed features home-schooling as much as anything else. It features parents sharing great ideas, it features daily plans and people sharing resources. AND it features parents telling us how hard they are finding it, especially if they are trying to work at the same time.
 Social Media features parents telling us how hard they are finding it, especially if they are trying to work at the same time All of these posts seem to make people feel bad about themselves, either they can’t achieve the lofty realms of the ‘perfect’ home-school, the one where the children are always engaged, are learning prescribed topics and ideas and where all interactions are calm and harmonious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting School — The Parent Survival Guide</title>
      <link>/news/2018/08/starting-school-the-parent-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018/08/starting-school-the-parent-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description>It’s completely normal for you to be anxious about how your child will cope when they start school, and for your child to be unsure about it as well. No matter how well you can act, even Nicole Kidman or Jonny Depp would find it hard to pretend that they’re cool with it all and hide all their nerves.
Don’t worry, read these tips to help in the first months and don’t sweat the small stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving tax on Childcare Fees</title>
      <link>/news/2018/07/saving-tax-on-childcare-fees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018/07/saving-tax-on-childcare-fees/</guid>
      <description>There are currently two ways of saving tax when it comes to childcare fees; the childcare vouchers scheme is being phased out and the current plan is to close it to new entrants from September 2018.
The best scheme for you depends on your circumstances (e.g. are both parents working, does the child get DLA, how much are the parents earning and how many children are there?)
So you need to check into which one will be the best for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beach Babies Orchard</title>
      <link>/news/2018/07/the-beach-babies-orchard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018/07/the-beach-babies-orchard/</guid>
      <description>The Orchard at Landbeach is a special place where we take the toddler and preschool children everyday. Much of our inspiration behind this is the Forest School practices of the Scandinavian countries.
In this area they can experience a much wilder environment than in the confines of our relatively manicured and controlled garden. They don’t have the usual garden toys of trikes, sandpit, and balls; rather they use all the resources available in the orchard, with the addition of only a few extras, such as string, buckets and spades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
